aratesh **Chakravar**i

Virtual Environments Lab, The Graduate School of Advanced Imaging Science, Chung Ang University, Seoul, South Korea

□(+91) 80954-64858 | Schakravarthi589@gmail.com | Homepage: https://chakravarthi589.github.io/

Summary.

Currently working as a research scholar and pursuing PhD (fulltime) at Virtual Environments Lab, GSAIM, Chung Ang University, Seoul. Prior to this, I have worked as assistant professor for five years at Engineering Institutes in Bengaluru, India. I hold Master's degree in Computer Networks and Engineering. Bachelors Degree in Information science and Engineering.

Work Experience _____

Virtual Environments Lab, GSAIM

Seoul, South Korea

RESEARCH SCHOLAR

• Currently working as a research scholar and pursuing full time PhD.

Aug. 2018 - PRESENT

- Working on a research project "Proxemics based pervasive Interactions for the wide-area and high-speed serial motion recognition", supported by Institute of Information & Communication Technology Planning and Evaluation grant funded by the Republic of Korea government.
- Have developed an indigenous human motion authoring and editing system.
- · Have involved continuously in research article publications and have attended several conferences and knowledge exchange pro-
- Have made contributions to open-source projects (Github) such as Visualization Toolkit (VTK) supported by Kitware Technologies®
- · Have actively involved in research article reviews.

Department of ISE, Jyothy Institue of Technology

Bengaluru, India

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR

July. 2015 - July. 2018

- Immaculately led and coordinated a technical forum "Graphics Day". Also, organized several technical talks, workshops and faculty development programs.
- Have played a key role in developing and maintaining Jyothy Institute's official websites.

Department of ISE, APS College of Engineering

Bengaluru, India

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR

June. 2013 - July. 2015

- Led and organized technical forum of ISE department "Tech-Spark" and "SPARKUP-2014"
- · Worked as a placement co-ordinator at department of placement & training, and gained experience in conducting various on campus & pool campus drives.

Education_

Chung Ang University

Seoul, South Korea

PhD in Computer Graphics and Virtual Reality

August 2018 - PRESENT

· Currently pursuing doctoral degree at Virtual Environments Lab, Graduate school of advanced imagining science, Chung Ang University, Seoul, South Korea.

The oxford College of Engineering, VTU

Bengaluru , India

MASTER OF TECHNOLOGY (M.TECH) IN COMPUTER NETWORKS AND ENGINEERING

- August. 2011 June. 2013 · A dissertation on "Interoperability issues between WiMAX and LTE" submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of master of technology.
- Got acquainted with Network Simulators (NS2 and NS3).
- Secured First Class with Distinction. (74.25 %)

A.P.S College of Engineering, VTU

Bengaluru, India

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (B.E) IN INFORMATION SCIENCE

September. 2007 - June. 2011

- A dissertation on "Design and Implementation of an Energy aware routing protocol for Wireless Sensor Networks (WSN)" submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the bachelor degree of engineering.
- Secured First Class. (64.5 %)

Skills

Programming C, C++, Python

SDK's/API's VTK, Qt, Autodesk FBX, Octave **Tools** 3ds Max (Biped Animation)

Hardware System MoCAP System - Xsens MTw Awinda, Perception Neuron

Arduino uno, Raspberry Pi

Databases MySQL

WebApp Development HTML, PHP, Javascript, FileZilla FTP Server

Research Interest

Domains

Human Motion Sensing Technology, Human Motion Analysis, Human Computer Interaction, Data Visualization, Virtual Reality, Machine Learning

Publications

Multi-Sensor Systems for Object Tracking, Sensors, MDPI

Journal Article

TITLE: "AN OPEN-SOURCE PLATFORM FOR HUMAN POSE ESTIMATION AND TRACKING USING A HETEROGENEOUS MULTI-SENSOR SYSTEM"

27 March 2021

https://doi.org/10.3390/s21072340

Sensors for Activity Recognition, Sensors, MDPI

Journal Article

TITLE: "FUSION OF MULTIPLE LIDARS AND INERTIAL SENSORS FOR THE REAL-TIME POSE TRACKING OF HUMAN Мотіон"

18 September 2020

https://doi.org/10.3390/s20185342

Computer Graphics and Virtual Reality, Applied Sciences, MDPI

Journal Article

TITLE: "MOTION-SPHERE: VISUAL REPRESENTATION OF THE SUBTLE MOTION OF HUMAN JOINTS"

16 September 2020

https://doi.org/10.3390/app10186462

The Korean Society of Mechanical Engineers TITLE: "SENSED UNIT MOTION BASED AUTHORING FOR THE PRECISE HUMAN MOVEMENTS" Conference, Seoul, South Korea

• https://www.dbpia.co.kr/journal/articleDetail?nodeId=NODE10527438

18-20 December 2020

IEEE Conference on Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces

Conference, Atlanta, GA, USA 22-26 March 2020

TITLE: "MOTIONNOTE: A NOVEL HUMAN POSE REPRESENTATION" • https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9090443

Korea Software Congress, The Korean Institute of Information Scientists and **Engineers**

Conference, Seoul, South Korea

TITLE: "QUATERNIONS BASED INTUITIVE VISUALIZATION FOR TRACKING WEIGHTLIFTING EXERCISES" • https://www.dbpia.co.kr/journal/articleDetail?nodeId=NODE09301824 22-26 December 2019

ACM SIGCHI Symposium on Engineering Interactive Computing Systems

TITLE: "PILOT EXPERIMENT OF A 2D TRAJECTORY REPRESENTATION OF QUATERNION-BASED 3D GESTURE TRACKING"

Conference, Valencia Spain 18-21 June 2019

• https://doi.org/10.1145/3319499.3328235

Karnataka Science and Technology Academy Conference

Conference, Bengaluru, India

TITLE: "AN IOT BASED SMART TRASH BIN AND AUTOMATED GARBAGE MONITORING SYSTEM FOR SMART CITIES IN ΙΝΟΙΔ"

18-19 January 2018

• https://reva.edu.in/ksta/#

IEEE International Advance Computing Conference

Conference, Bengaluru, India

TITLE: "INTENSIFYING THE LIFETIME OF WIRELESS SENSOR NETWORK USING A CENTRALIZED ENERGY ACCUMULATOR NODE WITH RF ENERGY TRANSMISSION"

12-13 June 2015

• https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/7154694

Internationl Journal of Engineering Research and Technology

Journal Article

TITLE: "SEAMLESS INTEROPERABILITY ACROSS LTE AND WIMAX USING VERTICAL HANDOVER MECHANISM"

20 June 2013

· https://www.ijert.org/seamless-interoperability-across-lte-and-wimax-using-vertical-handover-mech

Certifications

2021	Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate, Course certification authorized by Google®	Online, Coursera
2021	Python Programming, Course certification authorized by University of michigan	Online, Coursera
2021	Korean Language, Course certification authorized by Yonsei University	Online, Coursera
		Google
2018	Advanced Android Development and Designing Thinking, Certification authorized by Google®	Development
		Center, Bengaluru
2017	Android Fundamentals Faculty Training, Certification authorized by Koenig Solutions Ltd and	Koenig Solutions
	Google®	Ltd, Bengaluru
2015	Intel HPC Code Modernization , Certification authorized by Center for Development of Advanced	CDAC, Bengaluru
	Computing [®]	CDAC, Deligulara
2014	Faculty Enablement Program (FEP) on Foundation Program 4.0, Certification authorized by Infosys Limited®	Infosys
		Development
	mosys Emmed	Center, Bengaluru
2014	Microsoft Faculty Fellow, Certification authorized by Microsoft® and CITech	CITech, Bengaluru

Technical Talks

Blockchain and Internet of Things

Bhopal, Madhya Pradesh, India

UIT-RGPV 31st July 2021

AICTE Training and Learning (ATAL) Academy Sponsored Faculty Development Program, organized by Department of Computer Science and Engineering.

Blockchain of Things

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

BNMIT 18th January 2021

AICTE Training and Learning (ATAL) Academy Sponsored Faculty Development Program, organized by Department of Computer Science and Engineering.

Challenges and Research Directions for Blockchains

Salem, Tamilnadu, India

SONA COLLEGE OF TECHNOLOGY 10th February 2021

AICTE Sponsored Faculty Development Program, organized by Department of Computer Science and Engineering.

Human Computer Interaction in Virtual EnvironmentsBengaluru, Karnataka, India

RR Institue of Technology 17th August 2020

Faculty Development Program, organized by Department of Computer Science and Information Science Engineering.

Mobile App Development using Android Studio - Hands-on Session

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Sri Venkateshwara College of Engineering 24th February 2018

Indian Society For Technical Education sponsored Student Development Program, organized by Department of Computer Science and Engineering.

IOT and its Applications

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Dr. AIT 1st March 2017

Student Development Program, organized by Department of Computer Applications.

Opportunities in the field of IOT

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

BMS College of Engineering 6th March 2017

Technical Education Quality Improvement Programme of Government of India Sponsored Student Development Program, organized by Department of Computer Science and Engineering.

Programming and Application Development using Python

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

SIR M VISVESVARAYA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

11th March 2017

Student Development Program Organized by Department of Computer Applications.

Article Reviews

Journals MDPI - Sensors, Applied Science, Sustainability, Applied System Innovation, Vehicles, AI, Processes.

Elsevier - ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing

Conferences IEEE - ICECCME 2021

ACM - VRST 2021

Professional Body Membership

ISTE Lifetime member - International Society for Technology in Education

CSI Lifetime member - Computer Society of India

Achievements, Awards & Funding

ACHIEVEMENTS

2017 **Convener**, "Graphics Day 2017", An Intercollegiate Project Exhibition Bengaluru, India

2017 Co-Convener, Faculty Development Program on "OOP with Java for DAA lab and ARM Programming"

Bengaluru, India

regulations

2016 **Convener**, 5th National Conference on Emerging Trends in Engineering Technologies (ETET-2016) *Bengaluru, India*

STUDENT COLLABORATIONS & AWARDS

2018 **1st Place**, Project Exhibition, The 10th Annual Conference of Karnataka Science and Technology Academy held at REVA University

Bengaluru, India

2018 **2nd Place**, Project Exhibition, State level Engineering Project Exhibition held at BGS Institute of Karnataka, India

Technology Technology

Certificate of Merit, Project Exhibition, Unisys Cloud 20/20 V8
 Best Project, Project Exhibition, "TECH-STORM 2016" organized at GSSSET in association with IETE

Mysore, India

116 **Certificate of Merit,** Project Exhibition, Unisys Cloud 20/20 V7 Bengaluru, India

FUNDING

VTU, Financial Assistance sanctioned by the Visvesvaraya Technological University (VTU) for a project entitled "An IoT Based Smart Trash Bin and Automated Garbage Monitoring System for

Smart Cities in India"

Belagavi, India

KSCST, Project Funding Sanctioned under the 41st series of student project programme: 2017-18
 2017 (41st Series of SPP), from Karnataka State Council for Science and Technology. Project Title - "An IoT Based Smart Trash Bin and Automated Garbage Monitoring System for Smart Cities in India"

Bengaluru, India

Course Preference

Programming Languages C, C++, Python.

Data Analytics Data Visualization using Tableau, Data Analysis with R Programming.

Machine Learning Neural Networks, Support Vector Machines.

Virtual Reality 3D Models, 3D Interaction, AR/VR/MR/XR Technologies and Applications

Arduino uno, Raspberry Pi

Networks Data Communication, Computer Networks, Wireless Sensor Networks

Computer Graphics OpenGL, Visualization Toolkit (VTK)

Personal Details

Name Bharatesh Chakravarthi

Date of Birth 1989-05-05 Nationality Indian

Passport Status Valid Passport until 2031

Marital Status Married

Languages English, Kannada, Korean(Elementary)

Current Residence Seoul, South Korea

email chakravarthi589@gmail.com, bc05@cau.ac.kr

Contact Number (+91) 80954 64858, (+82) 10-6452-4858